Matt Coleman

Front-end Developer

D.O.B: 31st July 1988 **Tel:** 07905 404 858

Sex:MaleEmail:hello@matt-coleman.co.ukNationality:BritishGithub:github.com/matt3188

Summary

I am a strong and passionate front end developer with good communication skills and a keen eye for detail. I work well in a team just as well as I do on my own.

I like to create modular and portable code with a DRY approach and I also try and future proof my code as best I can.

My strengths include but are not limited too, HTML templating, CSS/SCSS, Javascript, Webpack, Grunt/Gulp. I have experience with Vue and React JS. I also have experience with Jira, Agile methodology, Git, RESTful APIs, SMACCS, Umbraco, Sitecore, Wordpress, Django and Drupal.

Skills

HTML, CSS/SCSS/LESS, Javascript, ES6, Typescript, NodeJS, NPM, Grunt, Gulp, Webpack, Browserify, Babel, Vue JS, React JS, Riot JS, BDD/TDD, RESTful API, SEO, Jade, Vagrant, Ansible, PHP, Django, SQL, XML, Yaml, JSON, WordPress, Drupal, TravisCI, Git, Slack, Photoshop, Illustrator, Sketch, Atom, Sublime Text, Brackets, VSCode.

Experience

Radley Yeldar (June 2019 - Present)

Lead Front-end Developer

After proving my worth as an integral part of the team and showing them my experience leading projects, RY promoted me to Lead front-end to push the team and introduce new ways working and newer technologies. So far I have introduced regular catch ups with my team to help them develop their careers and skills further, worked with the Umbraco and Front-end developers to create RY's first project with Vue JS, introduced RY to it's first permanent QA and helped him integrate Selenium and Mocha to their Vue JS project.

Radley Yeldar (Feb 2019 - June 2019)

Senior Front-end Developer

Joining RY in February I was put on their biggest client's project due to my experience at DARE. I worked with a team of Sitecore engineers, Project managers and a QA team to get the site up to a standard that we were happy with. I introduced ES6 to the project and re-wrote a lot of the JS to help meet the requirements set by the demanding client. A lot of the JS was not built in a sustainable or reusable way which made extending and maintaining it almost impossible. Working with the Sitecore Back end team to create and improve the APIs we were able to improve the user experience.

DARE (Feb 2018 - Feb 2019)

Senior Client Side Engineer

I currently lead the front end team on one of Dare's biggest accounts. Working with experience planners, designers and Sitecore engineers we are striving for a modular, flexible and robust library that can be used across the site. Built with React, our main focus is adding to the ever growing asset library of React components that is rendered serve side via Sitecore.

Spindrift (May 2017 - Feb 2018)

UI Developer

I predominantly worked on Oracle's Commerce Cloud (OCC). Spindrift are a full-service digital agency delivering Oracle's full commerce range. My day to day included working with some top brands such as Manchester United FC, Cluse Watches in the Netherlands and Home Choice in South Africa. The OCC platform uses Jade templating, Knockout JS, LESS and the OCC API. I collaborated with UX designers, CX developers and Project managers to create an omni channel ecommerce experience.

Dennis Publishing (August 2015 - May 2017)

Front-end Developer

Whilst I was at Dennis Publishing, I had the chance to work on their vast and eclectic portfolio. My day to day would include working on new features for their current Drupal distro, writing modules with Javascript to interact with the Drupal database and working with the commercial team to produce adverts that will appear on any one of the websites they maintained. I worked with Grunt extensively to produce a universal ad template generator which allowed the devs to create any one of the many ad formats they produced. It included tools like CSS minification, JS transpiling, linting and uglifying, optimising images and deploying the advert to the various end-points.

Other responsibilities included:

- Setting standards for advert creation, Javascript structuring and Drupal development.
- Developing rich HTML5 adverts for cross platform delivery using OO JavaScript, CSS3, SVG, Git, SASS, Video/Audio playback, and Responsive design.
- Leading the team in JavaScript, Grunt, CSS, command line usage and general development queries and questions.
- Writing both BDD and TDD tests.
- Using JS frameworks like Riot JS and RESTful API's to create better UI/UX on the front end.
- Implementing and writing Drupal modules.
- Code reviews for anything JavaScript.

Adnostic (August 2014 - August 2015)

Digital Designer/ Front-end Developer

During my time at Adnostic I was able to improve my JavaScript skills and was exposed to a lot of UI and UX principles. Working on smaller projects allowed me to get involved in a varied amount of work, from fully responsive adverts to ones with a heavy use of interaction or animation. Working in the advertising world helped me develop my knowledge and understanding of the users journey and how important it is to make sure it was as fluid as possible. I always ensured my code was as modular and reusable as possible. This allowed me to create adverts with certain common aspects that were favoured by their clients fairly quickly. My approach helped increase the teams efficiency and was recognised by senior management. My other responsibilities included:

- Developing rich HTML5 adverts for cross platform delivery, using OO JavaScript, CSS3, SVG, SASS, Video/Audio playback, Responsive design and Git.
- Creative input from concept to realisation.
- · Rapid prototyping.
- Liaising with 3rd party platforms and providers.
- Device testing and bug fixing.

Popcorn Web Design (February 2012 - August 2014)

Full stack Developer

When I first started at Popcorn I was responsible for all of their clients needs once their site had gone live. It was my job to help the client in any way possible with new work, features or maintenance that they might need. I would manage and delegate the work load between myself and the team. Throughout my time at Popcorn, I was given an ever increasing level of responsibility, from meeting

with clients and discussing their needs, to making their ideas a reality using the latest technologies and practices. This included building Wordpress themes, creating landing pages and building bespoke solutions to meet the client's brief. Other responsibilities included:

- Designing, developing and maintaining Wordpress sites.
- Writing Wordpress plugins.
- Using jQuery and CSS to enhance the user experience.

Education

BA Hons Graphic Design (2008 - 2011) Middlesex University

London NW4 4BT